<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Macro Chronicles: Economics, Markets, Dataviz</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Macro Chronicles: Economics, Markets, Dataviz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Damage Done to the Labor Market</title>
      <link>/blog/the-damage-done-to-the-labor-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/the-damage-done-to-the-labor-market/</guid>
      <description>The US unemployment rate (UR) has fallen for the last three months, fortunately snapping back from the official high of 14.7% in April, declining to 10.2% in July. Even excluding everyone that has gotten their old job back or has found a new position over the last several months, however, it&#39;s still the case that more people in the US have lost their job this year than during the depths of the Global Financial Crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muddling Through</title>
      <link>/blog/muddling-through/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/muddling-through/</guid>
      <description>Since this blog&#39;s last update on COVID-19 numbers, the US has made progress in the number of tests administered daily, and the positivity rate of testing appeared to stop increasing in July. The now large number of daily tests and the positivity rate in the high single digits, however, entails a significant amount of new cases each day. States walking back plans to reopen and the publics&#39; self-policing are moderating case growth, but the lack of a coordinated national plan to stamp out the virus means that most states will muddle through the next few months with outbreaks neither out of control nor much less prevalent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TSLA, the Moon&#39;s New Neighbor</title>
      <link>/blog/tsla-the-moons-new-neighbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tsla-the-moons-new-neighbor/</guid>
      <description>Tesla&#39;s share price has risen so far that it has settled down not far from the moon, and who knows how long it will spend outside the stratosphere. The chart below, indexing each stock price to 100 at the end of 2014, shows roughly that if the same amounts were invested in Tesla and other major automakers five and a half years ago, Tesla provided an almost 7x return while most others lost money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Trading and the Poster Boy of Retail Bros</title>
      <link>/blog/on-trading-and-the-poster-boy-of-retail-bros/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/on-trading-and-the-poster-boy-of-retail-bros/</guid>
      <description>When the market crashed in late-February and March, a lot of Americans decided it was time to open up a brokerage account or more actively trade their existing one. Apart from trading volumes, Tesla’s stock going to the moon, and Hertz’s rising share price as the company filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy, we can tell retail trading has increased by the interest people have expressed in their Google search bars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The American Surge</title>
      <link>/blog/the-american-surge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/the-american-surge/</guid>
      <description>We’re in the midst of a great, if somewhat semantic, debate about waves. Given a swift increase in the number of new COVID-19 cases each day across a large number of US states in June, commentators have sounded the alarm that The Second Wave is now upon us. Others, including Dr. Fauci, have emphasized that “we’re still in the first wave.”1 The first never passed to allow another to follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Sense of the Jobs Numbers</title>
      <link>/blog/making-sense-of-the-jobs-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/making-sense-of-the-jobs-numbers/</guid>
      <description>I have recently donated to the Real Justice PAC, which works to elect reform-minded prosecutors at the county and municipal level, and encourage you to consider also donating. Last week&#39;s US nonfarm payrolls report caused a lot of head scratching, as it showed total employment increased by 2.5 million jobs in May despite a range of other data points leading up to the report that suggested the economy continued to hemorrhage jobs last month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Far From Out of the Woods</title>
      <link>/blog/far-from-out-of-the-woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/far-from-out-of-the-woods/</guid>
      <description>There surely isn’t a country right now whose people aren’t collectively wondering when things will be totally back to normal, and whether things can ever be the kind of normal they were before. For countries that have battled the virus to a trickle of new cases or none at all, many appear well on their way in opening their economies up, yet their paths to normalcy resemble less a snapback than a slow, incremental recovery still constrained by uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Ben Bakkum, and I&amp;rsquo;m the author of Macro Chronicles. I live in New York and work on the data team at GiveDirectly, a nonprofit that operates cash transfer and basic income programs across seven countries in Africa and has provided disaster relief in the US, Puerto Rico, and the Bahamas.
Prior to GiveDirectly, I worked on the Private Bank Chief Investment Officer&amp;rsquo;s team at J.P. Morgan, where I contributed to macroeconomic and global financial market research and analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>You can use this page to put a license on the contents of your blog, like so:
 The MIT License (MIT)
Copyright (c) 2015 Nishanth Shanmughamnishanth.gerrard@gmail.com
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>