<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Macro Chronicles: Economics, Markets, Dataviz</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Macro Chronicles: Economics, Markets, Dataviz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercaps and the forces that drive them</title>
      <link>/blog/supercaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/supercaps/</guid>
      <description>h1{font-size: 30px;}h2{font-size: 29px;}body{font-size: 15px;font-family: &#39;Open Sans&#39;, sans-serif;}p{margin: 0 0 10.5px;margin-top: 0px;margin-right: 0px;margin-bottom: 25px;margin-left: 0px;line-height: 26px;}
IntroductionA breed of company has established itself, whose businesses are valued at such colossal amounts, that to call its members Supercaps would be more fitting than the Large- and Mega-cap labels traditionally used to describe firms with the biggest market capitalizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Ben Bakkum, and I&amp;rsquo;m the author of Macro Chronicles. I live in New York and work on the data team at GiveDirectly, a nonprofit that operates cash transfer and basic income programs across seven countries in Africa and has provided disaster relief in the US, Puerto Rico, and the Bahamas.
Prior to GiveDirectly, I worked on the Private Bank Chief Investment Officer&amp;rsquo;s team at J.P. Morgan, where I contributed to macroeconomic and global financial market research and analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>You can use this page to put a license on the contents of your blog, like so:
 The MIT License (MIT)
Copyright (c) 2015 Nishanth Shanmughamnishanth.gerrard@gmail.com
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>