<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Macro Chronicles: Economics, Markets, Dataviz</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Macro Chronicles: Economics, Markets, Dataviz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GameStop and the memestock discourse</title>
      <link>/blog/gamestop-and-the-memestock-discourse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/gamestop-and-the-memestock-discourse/</guid>
      <description>Everyone and their aunt’s goldendoodle have penned a substack piece or tweetstorm on the happenings in the market this week, so there’s hardly any original thoughts on the topic left to have, but it does feel as though 15 years from now we’ll all still sometimes pause to muse on the Great GameStop Short Squeeze of ’21. I can’t, in that case, help but take down a few notes on some of the memorable bits born out of current market conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobs -&gt; Rolling over</title>
      <link>/blog/jobs-rolling-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/jobs-rolling-over/</guid>
      <description>Nonfarm payrolls declined by 140,000 jobs in December, coming after the rebound in job growth steadily slowed during the second half of the year. December marks the first fall in employment since April’s collapse, as the high levels of COVID cases have buffeted employers. The headline unemployment rate stayed at 6.7%.
As shown in the chart above, with the recovery rolling over around the percentage of job losses reached in the depths of the recession caused by the Global Financial Crisis, the economy is a long, long way away from the health of the labor market pre-pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 -&gt; Inflection points</title>
      <link>/blog/covid-19-inflection-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/covid-19-inflection-points/</guid>
      <description>The fall brought with it a surge in virus cases, especially in the Midwest, yet daily positive test numbers averaged over a week appear to have recently rolled over in the most hard hit states. This is good news, given that typically once states have stopped the rise in daily new infections, the growth in cases has continued to slow over the short-term. The context of this surge relative to those of the spring and summer, however, is important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Detour -&gt; Which way will Pennsylvania swing?</title>
      <link>/blog/political-detour-which-way-will-pennsylvania-swing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/political-detour-which-way-will-pennsylvania-swing/</guid>
      <description>After mapping Florida&#39;s electoral history and looking at the outlook there for this cycle last week, I was curious what the equivalent charts for Pennsylvania would show. Pennsylvania was one of the three Rust Belt states that flipped in 2016, eroding the Blue Wall in the North that previously seemed unlikely gains for Republicans. Trump very narrowly carried Pennsylvania, Michigan, and Wisconsin, with less than 45,000 votes in each state differentiating the candidates and ultimately determining which way the electoral college swung.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Detour -&gt; Which way will Florida swing?</title>
      <link>/blog/political-detour-which-way-will-florida-swing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/political-detour-which-way-will-florida-swing/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s almost November, which often means Florida has the attention of poll watchers given the tradition of Federal elections in the state coming down to razer thin margins, typically with significant implications at the national level. This year, Florida is essentially a must-win for Trump to gain re-election. FiveThirtyEight now estimates that if Biden takes Florida, Trump has less than a 1 in 100 chance of coming out on top in electoral votes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>60 years of US population pyramids</title>
      <link>/blog/60-years-of-us-population-pyramids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/60-years-of-us-population-pyramids/</guid>
      <description>I recently went down a rabbit hole of Census Bureau (CB) data initially spurred by an interest in how the demographics of swing states are changing. I also just read Matt Yglesias&#39; One Billion Americans: The Case for Thinking Bigger, a call for a range of policies to push US population growth in a new direction. I ended up with the chart below, a picture of the past, present, and future demographics of the country combining five variables: (1) Population (2) Age (3) Race (4) Gender (5) Calendar year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 -&gt; Europe&#39;s Resurgence</title>
      <link>/blog/covid-19-europes-resurgence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/covid-19-europes-resurgence/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post from June called The American Surge, I wrote about the debate at the time over whether the US had entered a second wave given it seemed clear that the first wave to hit the country had never really passed. I also suggested that fire may be a more fitting metaphor and that &amp;quot;in the places where the fire has been brought down to a smoldering remnant, a handful of embers can still exist that erupt again when oxygen returns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Damage Done to the Labor Market</title>
      <link>/blog/the-damage-done-to-the-labor-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/the-damage-done-to-the-labor-market/</guid>
      <description>The US unemployment rate (UR) has fallen for the last three months, fortunately snapping back from the official high of 14.7% in April, declining to 10.2% in July. Even excluding everyone that has gotten their old job back or has found a new position over the last several months, however, it&#39;s still the case that more people in the US have lost their job this year than during the depths of the Global Financial Crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muddling Through</title>
      <link>/blog/muddling-through/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/muddling-through/</guid>
      <description>Since this blog&#39;s last update on COVID-19 numbers, the US has made progress in the number of tests administered daily, and the positivity rate of testing appeared to stop increasing in July. The now large number of daily tests and the positivity rate in the high single digits, however, entails a significant amount of new cases each day. States walking back plans to reopen and the publics&#39; self-policing are moderating case growth, but the lack of a coordinated national plan to stamp out the virus means that most states will muddle through the next few months with outbreaks neither out of control nor much less prevalent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TSLA, the Moon&#39;s New Neighbor</title>
      <link>/blog/tsla-the-moons-new-neighbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tsla-the-moons-new-neighbor/</guid>
      <description>Tesla&#39;s share price has risen so far that it has settled down not far from the moon, and who knows how long it will spend outside the stratosphere. The chart below, indexing each stock price to 100 at the end of 2014, shows roughly that if the same amounts were invested in Tesla and other major automakers five and a half years ago, Tesla provided an almost 7x return while most others lost money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Trading and the Poster Boy of Retail Bros</title>
      <link>/blog/on-trading-and-the-poster-boy-of-retail-bros/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/on-trading-and-the-poster-boy-of-retail-bros/</guid>
      <description>When the market crashed in late-February and March, a lot of Americans decided it was time to open up a brokerage account or more actively trade their existing one. Apart from trading volumes, Tesla’s stock going to the moon, and Hertz’s rising share price as the company filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy, we can tell retail trading has increased by the interest people have expressed in their Google search bars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The American Surge</title>
      <link>/blog/the-american-surge/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/the-american-surge/</guid>
      <description>We’re in the midst of a great, if somewhat semantic, debate about waves. Given a swift increase in the number of new COVID-19 cases each day across a large number of US states in June, commentators have sounded the alarm that The Second Wave is now upon us. Others, including Dr. Fauci, have emphasized that “we’re still in the first wave.”1 The first never passed to allow another to follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Sense of the Jobs Numbers</title>
      <link>/blog/making-sense-of-the-jobs-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/making-sense-of-the-jobs-numbers/</guid>
      <description>I have recently donated to the Real Justice PAC, which works to elect reform-minded prosecutors at the county and municipal level, and encourage you to consider also donating. Last week&#39;s US nonfarm payrolls report caused a lot of head scratching, as it showed total employment increased by 2.5 million jobs in May despite a range of other data points leading up to the report that suggested the economy continued to hemorrhage jobs last month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Far From Out of the Woods</title>
      <link>/blog/far-from-out-of-the-woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/far-from-out-of-the-woods/</guid>
      <description>There surely isn’t a country right now whose people aren’t collectively wondering when things will be totally back to normal, and whether things can ever be the kind of normal they were before. For countries that have battled the virus to a trickle of new cases or none at all, many appear well on their way in opening their economies up, yet their paths to normalcy resemble less a snapback than a slow, incremental recovery still constrained by uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>